https://www.giscorps.org/giscorps-privacy-policy/

skip to Main ContentTwitterFacebookLinkedInEmailBecome a VolunteerRequest VolunteersDONATE
Who we areGISCorps is a program of the Urban and Regional Information Systems Association (URISA), a United States-based 501(c)(3) nonprofit organization. Our website address is https://giscorps.org. To protect online privacy, GISCorps has implemented the following Privacy Policy (“Policy”). By accessing the website or providing your information to us, you accept and agree to the practices described in this Policy.What personal data we collect and why we collect itGISCorps collects personally identifiable information from you when you provide it to us by filling out a form on our website. This information includes name, address, email address, and professional information. GISCorps also collects and analyzes information on how visitors interact with our website in order to improve our site’s interface and content.Contact formsThe contact form on this website collects your first name, last name, and e-mail address. It sends that information to GISCorps via e-mail at info@giscorps.org to identify you as the e-mail’s sender. The information is not stored in a GISCorps database but may persist in GISCorps’s e-mail account like any other e-mail we receive.Partner Organization DataThe details you enter in the Request Volunteers form on this website are stored in GISCorps’s database and used by GISCorps staff and Core Committee members to contact you and manage your request. GISCorps will use your contact information to communicate with you about your request and to send periodic correspondence related to GISCorps news and events.GISCorps will also display a point on the “Our Missions” map on the home page of this website to show the approximate location of your project. This location data can be further generalized or omitted from the map entirely upon request.Your information will remain in our database until you ask us to remove it. Please see the How to Make a Data Request section for instructions.Volunteer DataThe details you enter in the Sign Up to Volunteer form on this website are stored in GISCorps’s database and used by GISCorps staff and Core Committee members to contact you, manage your volunteer profile, and match you with volunteer opportunities. GISCorps will use your contact information to contact you about volunteer opportunities and to send periodic correspondence related to GISCorps news and events.GISCorps aggregates volunteers by the state or country level to display participation on the “Our Volunteers” map on the home page of this website. GISCorps will never map or display addresses of individual volunteers on this website or anywhere else.Your information will remain in our database until you ask us to remove it. Please see the How to Make a Data Request section for instructions on requesting removal of your data.GIS Service Pledge DataThe details you enter in the Take the GIS Service Pledge form on this website are stored in GISCorps’s database and used by GISCorps staff and Core Committee members to contact you and administer your GIS Service Pledge. GISCorps will send your name, e-mail address, phone number, home address, and place of employment to Environmental Systems Research Institute (Esri) so that they can grant you an Esri software license as part of the GIS Servcie Pledge Program.Your information will remain in our database until you ask us to remove it. To withdraw from the GIS Service Pledge program and request that your information be deleted from our database, please send an email with the word “Withdraw” in the subject line to servicepledge@giscorps.org. To request a copy of your information, please send a request to servicepledge@giscorps.org with the words “Personal Data Request” in the subject line.Donation and Payment DataWhen you make a donation to GISCorps through this website, you are transferred to a form on the URISA website. The form collects your billing address and credit card information and passes it directly to a payment processor called Abila NetForum Pro. Abila does not sell, rent or share your information with third parties for their promotional use. More information on Abila’s policies can be found here. GISCorps and URISA do not access or store any of the billing or credit card information collected by Abila in the donation form, though we do keep a record of donor names and donation amounts.CookiesWith your explicit consent, GISCorps uses cookies to collect and analyze information on how visitors interact with our website in order to improve our site’s interface and content. Cookies are also used to pass your information from one page to the next as you navigate our website. You may opt out of having your information collected by cookies on our site at any time by clicking the Revoke Cookies tab at the bottom of our site. You may also set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies with the awareness that certain features may not function properly without the aid of cookies.Embedded content from other websitesPages on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, interactive maps, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.Links to other websitesThe GISCorps website contains links to other websites. This Policy applies only to our website, so please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites, and we are not liable for their misuse of personal information. We encourage you to be aware that when you go to another website you should carefully read their privacy policy.  Links to other sites do not imply GISCorps’ endorsement of the products or services, or privacy or security practices of those websites.How we share your dataGISCorps shares your data only with third parties with which we collaborate or contract to administer our organization, communications, and projects; these third parties include Esri, Slack, MailChimp, and G Suite. We will never sell, rent or share your information to anyone for promotional use or for purposes other than administering our organization and managing our projects. GISCorps may post articles about projects in which you participated as a volunteer or a partner agency on this website. If you or your organization is mentioned in an article, a GISCorps representative will contact you to obtain your approval and consent before doing so.How long we retain your dataInformation collected in the Sign Up to Volunteer, Take the GIS Service Pledge, and Request Volunteers forms will remain in our database until you ask us to remove it. Please see the How to Make a Data Request section for instructions on requesting removal of your data.Our Security Measures to Protect Your Personal InformationWe are committed to taking reasonable efforts to secure the information that you choose to provide us, and we use a variety of security procedures to help protect against unauthorized access to or alteration, disclosure, or destruction of personal information. We restrict access to personal information to our Core Committee members, employees, contractors and servicers who need to know the information to operate, develop, or improve our services.Unfortunately, no transmission of personal information over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.  Accordingly, and despite our efforts, GISCorps cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, or to or from our online services.  GISCorps has no responsibility or liability for the security of information transmitted via the Internet. If you have questions about this Policy or the security of your personal information, please contact us as indicated under the “Contact Us” section below.How  long  we retain your  dataInformation collected in the Sign Up to Volunteer, Take the GIS Service Pledge, and Request Volunteers forms will remain in our database until you ask us to remove it. Please see the How to Make a Data Request section for instructions on requesting removal of your data.What rights you have over your dataYour personal data belongs to you, and you have the following rights:You have the right to request a copy of your personal data from GISCorps.You have the right to request that GISCorps correct any data that you believe is inaccurate or incomplete.You have the right to request that GISCorps erase your personal data.You have the right to object or restrict to GISCorps’s processing of your personal data.You have the right to request that GISCorps transfer the data we have collected to another organization or directly to you.You have the right to object to or restrict GISCorps’s processing of your personal data.You have the right to request that GISCorps transfer the data we have collected to another organization or directly to you.You have the right not to be subject to any decision based on profiling, however, GISCorps does not use volunteer, partner, or website visitor data to drive any automated decision making or profiling.You have the right to withdraw consent.  However, if you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent. If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us.How to make a data requestYou may request that your personal data be removed from our database at any time by emailing recruit@giscorp.org and including the word “PERSONAL DATA REMOVAL REQUEST” in the subject line.You may also request a copy of your data by emailing recruit@giscorps.org and including the words “PERSONAL DATA COPY REQUEST” in the subject line.You may request changes to your personal data by emailing recruit @giscorps.org and including the words “PERSONAL DATA CHANGE REQUEST” in the subject line.Finally, you may opt out of having your information collected by cookies on our site at any time by clicking the Revoke Cookies tab at the bottom of our site.ModificationsWe may amend this Policy from time to time without prior notice.  If we decide to change this Policy, we will post those changes on our home page so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it, so please review it periodically. Your continued use of our website will be deemed to be your agreement to the changed terms.Contact UsIf you have any questions about this Policy or our treatment of the information you provide us, please contact as at:Contact: GISCorps Core CommitteeAddress: 701 Lee Street, Suite 680, Des Plaines, IL, 60016, USAPhone: + 1 (847) 824-6300Email:  info@giscorps.orgLast updated November 9, 2019. New & Ongoing ProjectsGISCorps ProjectsGIS Service Pledge ProjectsHOT ProjectsProjects by TypeApplication DevelopmentArtificial Intelligence/Machine LearningCapacity BuildingCartographyConservationCrowdsourcingCultural ResourcesData Collection/CreationDisaster ResponseGSDIHOT/OSMHumanitarian ResponseImage processing/analysisK-12 EducationNatural ResourcesNeeds AssessmentOpen SourcePublic HealthRemote SensingSocial JusticeSocial MediaSpatial AnalysisSpatial Data Processing and Quality ControlSustainabilitySystem ArchitectureTrainingUser SupportWeb GISProjects by Year 2020 (40)
2019 (30)
2018 (26)
2017 (14)
2016 (13)
2015 (17)
2014 (12)
2013 (14)
2012 (11)
2011 (10)
2010 (6)
2009 (8)
2008 (9)
2007 (7)
2006 (1)
2005 (10)
2004 (2)
Have an idea for using your GIS skills to support a nonprofit you love? Take the GIS Service Pledge! © GISCorps 2009 701 Lee Street, Suite 680 Des Plaines, IL, 60016, USA (847) 824-6300Who We AreOur HistoryOur TeamOur VolunteersOur PartnersOur SupportersOur Organizing Principles and PoliciesOur Code of ConductURISA’s GovernanceWhat We DoNew and Ongoing ProjectsCompleted ProjectsNAPSG Foundation Disaster Reponse ProjectsGIS Service Pledge ProjectsHumanitarian OpenStreetMap Team ProjectsGet InvolvedBecome a VolunteerBecome a Friend of GISCorpsSupport GISCorpsOur SupportersTake the GIS Service PledgeHumanitarian OpenStreetMap Team ProjectsSpread The WordRequest VolunteersNewsNewslettersAnnual ReportMinutes From Our MeetingsPhoto and Video GalleryAwardsPublicationsContact Us
Back To Top We use cookies to ensure that we give you the best experience on our website. Click Yes if that's okay with you, and No if you'd prefer that we did not use cookies. You can change your answer at any time. Privacy policyYesNoPrivacy policy
